# LOOMONI MORWO

# **Software Engineer**

Dar es salaam, Tanzania

Mobile: +255765844637/+255714695956

Email: loomonimorwo@gmail.com

Links: LinkedIn, GitHub

Software engineer with 4+ years of experience in developing software solutions ranging from small scale to complex and large scale. Participated in designing and implementing system architectures and solutions for rapid scaling. I have significant experience working in startups and fast-moving teams with fixed deadlines.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Jan 2019 – Present

Kalen Technology Solutions, Dar es salaam, Tanzania

- Developed, tested, implemented and maintained high-quality business systems and software solutions on various platforms in response to the story flow across sprints, adhering to established methodologies and practices
- Overhauled continuous integration (CI) and continuous delivery (CD) pipeline which increased code delivery speed by 10% using Jenkins and GitHub Actions
- Provided connectivity that improved system functionality and managed complex code by installing API endpoints for more than 10 web applications.
- Built applications that scaled up to 3M+ users and communicating with cross-functional teams regarding the product and design.
- Performed architecturally compliant technical design and requirements as received in the story
- Oversaw a team of 2 engineers to write factored clean and scalable code using company stack such as Python (Odoo), Php (Laravel), Django, react js, and Docker

### Part time Back-End Engineer

June 2020 - Oct 2021

DeJNG Company Limited, Dar es salaam, Tanzania

- Created development solutions using JavaScript and Python by working alongside a team of 2 developers in an agile environment.
- Designed and coded complex backend service using cloud functions which simplified the connectivity between firebase and mobile applications by 20%
- Led a team of 3 engineers to build software solutions based on requirements received from different clients
- Teamed up with current clients to understand needs for improved business functionality on the existing software applications
- Developed REST Web services to make internet calls simple and easy for 4K clients to access using standard HTTP URIs.

PROJECTS DONE

## Wakala System and Android & iOS app for Kalen

Dec 2022 - current

Position: Software Engineer

- The system manage agent daily transaction, the app is developed to manage in and out transaction by sending a transaction message to the system to process whether is the out or in transaction, the app also takes in opening and closing cash for both hand and phone cash.
- The system gives daily reports.

- Tech stack used Laravel with it is Rest API, Flutter for Mobile App
- Database used MySQL.

# Web portal for Mr. Jou Ultra Sports

November 2022 - December 2022

Position: Software Engineer

- Project Link: <a href="https://mrjouultrasports.co.tz/">https://mrjouultrasports.co.tz/</a>
- Develop web portal for Mr Jou Ultra Sports organization which had 2 component Backend for content management and front end for the public
- Used the following tech stack to develop the solution; Laravel (PHP), Bootstrap 5, jQuery, JavaScript and HTML/CSS and SASS
- Database used was MySQL

### **Development of Tanzania Tennis Association web portal (TTA)**

September 2022 – October 2022

Position: Software Engineer

- Project Link: <a href="https://ttatz.co.tz/">https://ttatz.co.tz/</a>
- Develop web portal for Mr Jou Ultra Sports organization which had 2 component Backend for content management and front end for the public
- Used the following tech stack to develop the solution; Laravel (PHP), Bootstrap 5, jQuery, JavaScript and HTML/CSS and SASS
- Database used was MySQL

# M and E Development System for CDF (ERP)

August 2022 - Dec 2022

Position: Lead Software Engineer

- Led a team of 3 engineers to develop a responsive user interface that takes total project per specified time, all goals that are to be achieved, outcomes, output and all activities to be done to achieve a specified goal on a certain project, but all it gives report on daily task, each project as per need of CDF, it also have a dashboard for visualization of progress project and task.
- Tech stack used is Python (Odoo), HTML/CSS, JQuery, etc.
- Database used Postgress (pgAdmin III)

# Re-engineering of Uganda Revenue Authority web portal

April 2022 - Oct 2022

Position: Software Engineer

- Participate in a team of 3 engineers to re-develop a responsive user interface web portal with proper content management system which increased collection of taxes by 10%
- Built client relationship management system on the front facing side using Node js, JavaScript Dom functions and HTML/CSS
- Tech stack used WordPress, HTML/CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap 5, .etc.

# Integrated Monitoring and Evaluation management system for Ministry of Forestry and Natural Resources in Malawi Jan 2022 - April 2022

Position: Software Engineer

- Involved in development of the system which has three main component M&E information system, Knowledge management platform and Training platform.
- Tech stack used PHP, HTML/CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap 5, .etc.

Paralegal apps for provision of legal aid services to local and urban areas in Tanzania (2 Mobile apps, I web app)

March 2021 – Sept 2021

Position: Software Engineer

- Participated in development of the system aimed at providing legal aid services for people around 40k from the rural areas in Tanzania.
- Overhauled the real time connectivity between two mobile apps and web app which increased service availability by 10%
- Tech stack used Django, React js, HTML/CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, React Native, Firebase, GitHub and GitHub Actions, Elastic Search, Docker

# Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) solution for Kuringe Group, Tanzania Jan 2021 – March 2021

Position: Software Engineer

- Documented processes and procedures for business process automation as specified in SRS
- Collaborated with 2 other engineers to develop 8 modules of the system including (Accounting, Human resources, Payroll, Cash Request, Budget, Booking, Asset and Inventory management) which increased company revenue by 10%
- Tools used includes Odoo, xml and JavaScript, Nginx, Gunicorn, GitHub, Jenkins

# SME's Business management app for Finca Microfinance Bank in Tanzania Jan 2019 – March 2019 Position: Software Engineer

- Developed android-based business management app for small and medium enterprises which fasten the business process by 3%
- Participated in system security audit and problem identification of the company
- Technologies used includes React Native, React js, Rest api, GCP and material ui

# Development of HRIS (Human Resource Information System) for Legal services AID (LSF)

Sept 2021 - Jan 2022

Position: Lead Software Engineer

- An HRM Information System that provides core features to manage crucial organization asset-people. Its
  features are: Administration, Personal Information register, Employee Self Service, Smart PDF reports
  generation, Staff leaves management, Time sheet and attendance, Overtime, Employee evaluation and
  many others
- Tech stack used is Python (Odoo), HTML/CSS, JQuery, etc.
- Database used Postgress (pgAdmin III)

# **Shule Tanzania Mobile app**

Jun 2018 - sept 2018

Position: Software Engineer

- Lead a team of 4 engineers to develop android-based mobile application for school management which had 4 modules.
- Technologies used includes Android Studio, Firebase

# Star Cessna Online store (E-commerce web app) (Link)

Jan 2022 - Feb 2022

Position: Consultant

- Collaborated with 1 one other engineer to build e commerce web app(Online store) for Airline Parts and Accessories Which increased company sales and revenue by 10%.
- Used the following tech stack to develop the solution; WordPress, PhP, Bootstrap 5, jQuery, JavaScript and HTML/CSS
- Overhauled payment integration with PayPal to smoothen the transaction process for the products on the web app(online store)

Web portal for Tanzania Human Rights Defenders Coalition (THRDC) (Link)

Aug 2022 - sept 2022

- Collaborated with 1 one other engineer to develop web portal for THRDC organization which had 2 component Backend for content management and front end for the public
- Performed system integration via API gateway between the web portal and another membership system which simplified data flow between the two systems
- Used the following tech stack to develop the solution; Laravel, Bootstrap 5, jQuery, JavaScript and HTML/CSS and SASS

# 4 Web portals for Departments/Institutions of University of Dar es salaam

Jan 2021 - sept 2021

Position: Consultant

- Led a team of 2 other engineers to develop 4 web portals for the departments/institutions of University of Dar es salaam which are CSE web portal (<u>Link</u>), ETE web portal (<u>Link</u>), ISIRG web portal (<u>Link</u>) and UDASA web portal (<u>Link</u>), Which had 2 components each Backend for content management and front end for the public.
- Used the following tech stack to develop the solutions; Laravel, Bootstrap 5, jQuery, JavaScript and HTML/CSS and SASS
- Reviewed to code quality of other engineers to ensure best practices which increased system performance by 2%

# 2 Web portals for departments of Cybertz company Limited

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020

Position: Software Engineer

- Led a team of 3 engineers to develop 2 web portals for departments of Cybertz company which had 2 component Backend for content management and front end for the public
- Performed Search Engine Optimization for web portals which increased system visibility to the public by 10%
- Used the following tech stack to develop the solution; Laravel, Bootstrap 5, jQuery, JavaScript and HTML/CSS and SASS

#### **Web portal for Quantum Consulting Microfinance startup**

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

Position: Software Engineer

- Participated with 1 one other engineer to develop web portal for quantum Consulting company which had 2 component Backend for content management and front end for the public
- Tech stacks used include Laravel, Bootstrap 5, ¡Query, JavaScript and HTML/CSS and SASS

EDUCATION

# University of Dar es salaam, Tanzania

Nov 2017-July 2020

Bachelor of Science — Computer Science

SKILLS

- Php (Laravel) | Python | Django | REST API | Odoo (4 Years)
- JIRA | Scrum
- SQL|ORM
- MySQL | PostgreSQL | Oracle | Cloud Sql
- GHAPHQL
- FLUTTER | REACT NATIVE
- React js | Next js | Typescript | jQuery | Node js
- GCP | AWS | Digital Ocean | Cpanel

- JavaScript | CSS | SASS| HTML | Bootstrap | Material UI | Tailwind CSS
- Laravel | PHP | WordPress
- Docker | Kubernetes | Jenkins | GitHub| Bitbucket | GitHub Actions | Redis | Terraform
- Java | Elastic search
- Microservice Architecture | gRPC | kafka
- Problem-solving | Communication skills | Strong analytical skills

#### LANGUAGES

- English Fluent
- Swahili Native